Inventory of the A. Piatt Andrew papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1885-1936 (Box 2-17)
  - Wile, Fred W., 1931 (Folder 16: 13)
  - Willard, Charles H., 1931 (Folder 16: 14)
  - Willetts, William A., 1911 (Folder 16: 15)
  - Williams, Constance, 1929-1935 (Folder 16: 16)
  - Williams, James T., Jr., 1913-1924 (Folder 16: 17)
  - Williams, Jesse Lynch, 1906 (Folder 16: 18)
  - Wilson, Lucy, 1911-1913 (Folder 16: 19)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, 1913-1914 (Folder 16: 20)
  - Winsor, Robert, Jr., 1905 (Folder 17: 1)
  - Wolcott, Samuel H., 1905 (Folder 17: 2)
  - Wolcott, William Prescott, 1905 (Folder 17: 3)
  - Wolfe, Henry C., 1932 (Folder 17: 4)
  - Wood, Leonard, 1920-1921 (Folder 17: 5)
  - Woodbury, George, 1935 (Folder 17: 6)
  - Young, Benjamin Loring, 1921-1928 (Folder 17: 7)
  - Young, Hugh H., 1933-1935 (Folder 17: 8)
- Speeches and Writings, 1893-1935 (Box 17-20)
  Contains articles and speeches
  Arranged chronologically
  - "Ivy Oration," Princeton College, Princeton, New Jersey, 1893 (Folder 17: 9)
  - Valedictory address, Princeton College, Princeton, New Jersey, 1893 (Folder 17: 10)
  - Notes on economics, 1898 (Folder 17: 11-12)
  - "The End of the Mexican Dollar," Quarterly Journal of Economics, 1904 May (Folder 17: 13)
  - "The Benefits and Blunders of the Banking Bill,", 1908 (Folder 17: 14)
  - "A Discounted Currency and Foreign Trade,", 1910 (Folder 17: 15)
  - "Banking Systems and Currency Reform," address to the Commercial Club of Cincinnati, 1910 January 22 (Folder 17: 16)
  - Address to the South Carolina Bankers' Association, Aiken, South Carolina, 1910 April 9 (Folder 17: 17)
  - Interview, 1910 September 10 (Folder 17: 18)
  - "The Problem before the National Monetary Commission," Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1910 November (Folder 17: 19)
  - Address to the Academy of Political Science, New York City, 1910 November 11 (Folder 17: 20)
  - "The Suggested Plan for Banking Legislation," address, 1911 (Folder 18: 1)
  - The Purpose and Origin of the Proposed Banking Legislation, 1911 (Folder 18: 2)
  - Address to the National Board of Trade, Washington, D. C., 1911 January 18 (Folder 18: 3)
  - Address to the American Institute of Banking, New York City, 1911 February 11 (Folder 18: 4)
  - Address to the Pennsylvania Bankers' Association, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1911 June 15 (Folder 18: 5)
  - Address to the Maryland Bankers' Association, Deer Park, Maryland, 1911 June 21 (Folder 18: 6)
  - Address to the Indiana Bankers' Association, Indianapolis, Indiana, 1911 October 25 (Folder 18: 7)
  - "Cooperation in American Banking," Moody's Magazine, 1911 November (Folder 18: 8)
  - "The Relation of the National Reserve Association to the Treasury," address to the American Bankers' Association, New Orleans, Louisiana, 1911 November 21 (Folder 18: 9)
  - "The Bryanized Banking Bill,", 1913 June 25 (Folder 18: 10)
  - "The Crux of the Currency Question," Yale Review, 1913 July (Folder 18: 11)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, 1913 July 7 (Folder 18: 12)
  - "The Banking Bill as It Passed in the House," Boston Evening Transcript, 1913 October 8 (Folder 18: 13)
  - "Why I Am a Republican,", 1914 February 5 (Folder 18: 14)
  - Memorial Day address, Rockport, Massachusetts, 1914 May 30 (Folder 18: 15)
  - "The Crux of the Immigration Question," North American Review, 1914 June (Folder 18: 16)
  - "For Love of France," The Outlook, 1916 December 27 (Folder 18: 17)
  - Speech commemorating George Washington, 1919 (Folder 18: 18)
  - Speech concerning the League of Nations, 1920 (Folder 18: 19)
  - Campaign speeches, 1921 (Folder 18: 20-21)
  - Speech concerning American Legion pilgrimage to France, 1921 October 27 (Folder 18: 22)
  - Speeches to Republican meetings, 1922 (Folder 18: 23-24)
  - Speech for dedication of church carillon, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1922 July (Folder 18: 25)
  - Speech to Republican rally, Salem, Massachusetts, 1922 November 4 (Folder 18: 26)
  - Armistice Day speech, 1922 November 11 (Folder 18: 27)
  - Speech to veterans of Spanish American War, 1923 (Folder 18: 28)
  - Speech, Haverhill Chamber of Commerce, Haverhill, Massachusetts, 1923 June 5 (Folder 18: 29)
  - Speech, Republican regional conference, Salem, Massachusetts, 1923 June 1 (Folder 18: 30)
  - Speech on return from visit to France, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1923 November 1 (Folder 18: 31)
  - Speech to Massachusetts Women's Republican Club, Boston, Massachusetts, 1923 November 19 (Folder 18: 32)
  - "Child Labor Debate,", 1924 (Folder 18: 33)
  - Speech on Child Labor Amendment, 1924 (Folder 18: 34)
  - Address to St. John the Baptist Society meeting, Salem, Massachusetts, 1924 August 31 (Folder 18: 35)
  - Speech to Salem Rotary Club, Salem, Massachusetts, 1924 September 2 (Folder 18: 36)
  - Speech to post office employees, Haverhill, Massachusetts, 1924 September 4 (Folder 18: 37)
  - Speech to Women's Republican Club, Haverhill, Massachusetts, 1924 September 4 (Folder 18: 38)
  - Speech on Child Labor Amendment, 1924 October 7 (Folder 18: 39)
  - Speech on Child Labor Amendment, Women's Club, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1924 October 10 (Folder 18: 40)
  - Speech to Women's Republican Club, Newburyport, Massachusetts, 1924 October 17 (Folder 19: 1)
  - Speech to Women's Republican Club, Salem, Massachusetts, 1924 October 28 (Folder 19: 2)
  - Speech to Republican rally, Salem, Massachusetts, 1924 October 31 (Folder 19: 3)
  - Speech to Women's Republican Club, Beverly, Massachusetts, 1924 November 3 (Folder 19: 4)
  - "France and America Today,", 1925 (Folder 19: 5)
  - Speech for dedication ceremony, Gloucester Armory, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1925 May 8 (Folder 19: 6)
  - Memorial Day address, Beverly, Massachusetts, 1925 May 30 (Folder 19: 7)
  - Remarks, Essex County Women's Republican Club, Marblehead, Massachusetts, 1925 June 23 (Folder 19: 8)
  - Speech to Essex Republican Club, Essex, Massachusetts, 1925 July 29 (Folder 19: 9)
  - Campaign speech, 1926 (Folder 19: 10)
  - Speech on Congressional legislation, 1926 (Folder 19: 11)
  - Speech to American Legion meeting, 1926 (Folder 19: 12)
  - Speech, Lincoln's birthday dinner, Essex County Republican Club, Salem, Massachusetts, 1926 February 12 (Folder 19: 13)
  - Memorial Day address, 1926 May 30 (Folder 19: 14)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, 1926 July 19 (Folder 19: 15)
  - Speech, Elks' banquet, Haverhill, Massachusetts, 1927 June 6 (Folder 19: 16)
  - Speech, American Legion banquet, Lawrence, Massachusetts, 1926 June 8 (Folder 19: 17)
  - Speech, Salem tercentenary banquet, Salem, Massachusetts, 1926 July 7 (Folder 19: 18)
  - Armistice Day address, Women's Republican Club of Massachusetts, 1926 November 11 (Folder 19: 19)
  - "Changing Thought on the War Debts,", 1927 (Folder 19: 20)
  - Interview on French war debt question, 1927 (Folder 19: 21)
  - Speech, American Legion dinner, 1927 April 6 (Folder 19: 22)
  - Memorial Day address, 1927 May 30 (Folder 19: 23)
  - "Should the Debt Settlements Be Revised?" address, American Economic Association, Washington, D.C., 1927 December 29 (Folder 19: 24)
  - Campaign speeches, 1928 (Folder 19: 25-26)
  - Speech to Essex Club, 1928 (Folder 19: 27)
  - Speech, American Legion convention, 1928 (Folder 19: 28)
  - "Shall the Records of the World War Be Preserved?", 1928 (Folder 19: 29)
  - Address to Middlesex Club, Boston, Massachusetts, 1928 January 23 (Folder 19: 30)
  - Campaign speech, 1928 October (Folder 19: 31)
  - Speech to Boston City Club, Boston, Massachusetts, 1928 October 18 (Folder 19: 32)
  - Speech to Republican rally, Haverhill, Massachusetts, 1928 October 22 (Folder 19: 33)
  - Armistice Day speech, American Legion convention, Plymouth, Massachusetts, 1928 November 11 (Folder 19: 34)
  - Speech commemorating tercentenary of Marblehead, Massachusetts, 1929 (Folder 19: 35)
  - Speech to Republican meeting, 1929 (Folder 19: 36)
  - Speech to Essex Republican Club, Marblehead, Massachusetts, 1929 June 12 (Folder 19: 37)
  - Speech to American Legion meeting, 1929 August (Folder 19: 38)
  - Address, Harding memorial meeting, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1929 August 10 (Folder 19: 39)
  - Armistice Day speech, Amesbury, Massachusetts, 1929 November 11 (Folder 19: 40)
  - Speech, horticultural show, Manchester, Massachusetts, 1930 (Folder 19: 41)
  - Speech for building dedication, Salem, Massachusetts, 1930 (Folder 19: 42)
  - Speech on prohibition, Haverhill, Massachusetts, 1930 (Folder 19: 43)
  - Speech, Essex Club dinner, Salem, Massachusetts, 1930 April 11 (Folder 19: 44)
  - Speech, Jewish banquet, 1930 June (Folder 19: 45)
  - "Concerning the Eighteenth Amendment," joint meeting of Rotary Clubs, Amesbury, Massachusetts, 1930 July 17 (Folder 19: 46)
  - Speech commemorating tercentenary of Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1930 August 20 (Folder 19: 47)
  - Speech, mayor's luncheon, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1930 August 28 (Folder 19: 48)
  - Radio talk, 1930 November 2 (Folder 19: 49)
  - Speech on prohibition, 1931 (Folder 19: 50)
  - "The Wickersham Commission Blazes the Trail for the Republican Party," Middlesex Club, Boston, Massachusetts, 1931 February 12 (Folder 20: 1)
  - "The American Tradition of Home Rule," radio address, National Broadcasting Company, 1931 December 13 (Folder 20: 2)
  - Address, Essex Republican Club meeting, Topsfield, Massachusetts, 1931 October 21 (Folder 20: 3)
  - Campaign speech, 1932 (Folder 20: 4)
  - Speech to American Legion meeting, 1932 (Folder 20: 5)
  - Speech, Republican Council dinner, Amesbury, Massachusetts, 1932 April 19 (Folder 20: 6)
  - Speech to Republican rally, Salem, Massachusetts, 1932 September 8 (Folder 20: 7)
  - Address, Lafayette monument dedication, Haverhill, Massachusetts, 1932 September 17 (Folder 20: 8)
  - Speech, Federal Building cornerstone ceremony, Salem, Massachusetts, 1932 September 21 (Folder 20: 9)
  - Armistice Day address, Newburyport, Massachusetts, 1933 November 11 (Folder 20: 10)
  - Speech, Essex County Women's Republican Club, Danvers, Massachusetts, 1934 June (Folder 20: 11)
  - Speech, Beverly Republican Clubs, Beverly, Massachusetts, 1934 July 14 (Folder 20: 12)
  - Speech, swimming pool dedication, Salem, Massachusetts, 1934 July 15 (Folder 20: 13)
  - Speech to Republican rally, Haverhill, Massachusetts, 1934 November 2 (Folder 20: 14)
  - Armistice Day address, Beverly, Massachusetts, 1934 November 12 (Folder 20: 15)
  - Speech to meeting in honor of Frank Knox, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1935 (Folder 20: 16)
- Treasury Department file, 1908-1912 (Box 20-23)
  Contains correspondence, press releases, reports, subject file, and transcripts of hearings
  Arranged chronologically by position held by A. Piatt Andrew and by physical form thereunder
  - National Monetary Commission file, 1908-1909
    - Correspondence, 1908-1909 (Folder 20: 17)
    - Report, 1909 (Folder 20: 18)
  - Director of the United States Mint file, 1909-1910
    - Correspondence, 1909-1910 (Folder 20: 19)
    - Press release, 1910 (Folder 20: 20)
  - Assistant Secretary of the Treasury file, 1910-1912
    - Correspondence, 1910-1912
      - General, 1910-1912
        - 1910 (Folder 20: 21)
        - 1911 (Folder 20: 22)
        - 1912 (Folder 20: 23-24)
      - MacVeagh, Franklin, 1910-1912
        - 1910 (Folder 21: 1-5)
        - 1911 (Folder 21: 6-10)
        - 1912 (Folder 22: 1-3)
      - Taft, William Howard, 1912 (Folder 22: 4)
        Includes Andrew's letter of resignation and related correspondence
    - Press releases, 1910-1912 (Folder 22: 5)
    - Reports, 1910-1911 (Folder 22: 6)
    - Subject file, 1910-1912
      - Aldrich Plan, 1910-1912 (Folder 22: 7)
      - American Economic Association, 1911-1912 (Folder 22: 8)
      - Bond issues, 1910-1911
        - 1910 (Folder 22: 9)
        - 1911 (Folder 22: 10-12)
      - National Monetary Commission, 1911-1912 (Folder 23: 1)
      - Western Economic Association, 1911 (Folder 23: 2)
    - Transcripts of hearings, 1912 (Folder 23: 3)
- Political campaign file, 1913-1914 (Box 23-24)
  Contains correspondence, itineraries, lists of supporters, press releases, publicity materials, and speeches
  - Correspondence, 1913-1914
    - 1913 (Folder 23: 4-5)
    - 1914 (Folder 23: 6-10, Folder 24: 1-7)
  - Itineraries, 1914 (Folder 24: 8)
  - Lists of supporters, 1914 (Folder 24: 9)
  - Press releases, 1914 (Folder 24: 10)
  - Publicity materials, 1914 (Folder 24: 11)
  - Speeches, 1914 (Folder 24: 12)
- American Field Service file, 1914-1989 (Box 25-26)
  Contains account, appeal, art work, bulletins, clippings, correspondence, financial records, minutes of meetings, and reports
  - Account by Andrew Gray, "The Birth of the American Field Service,", 1989 (Folder 25: 1)
  - Appeal, 1915 (Folder 25: 2)
  - Art work, 1917 (Folder 25: 3)
  - Bulletins, 1916-1917 (Folder 25: 4)
  - Clippings, 1916-1922 (Folder 25: 5)
  - Correspondence, 1915-1935
    - 1915 (Folder 25: 6)
    - 1916 (Folder 25: 7)
    - 1917 (Folder 25: 8)
    - 1918 (Folder 25: 9)
    - 1919 (Folder 25: 10)
    - 1920 (Folder 25: 11)
    - 1921 (Folder 25: 12)
    - 1922 (Folder 25: 13)
    - 1923 (Folder 25: 14)
    - 1924 (Folder 26: 1-2)
    - 1925 (Folder 26: 3-4)
    - 1926 (Folder 26: 5-6)
    - 1927-1929 (Folder 26: 7)
    - 1930-1935 (Folder 26: 8)
  - Financial records, 1922-1932 (Folder 26: 9)
  - Minutes of meetings, 1922-1924 (Folder 26: 10)
  - Reports, 1922-1928 (Folder 26: 11)
  - Campaign literature, 1922-1930 (Folder 27: 1)
  - Correspondence, 1921-1936
    - General, 1924-1936
      - Letters of condolence and sympathy received by Congressman Andrew's office during his final illness and after his death, 1936 (Folder 27: 2-3)
      - Letters of criticism, 1924-1934 (Folder 27: 4)
    - Chronological file, 1921-1936
      - 1921 (Folder 27: 5)
      - 1922 (Folder 27: 6-7)
      - 1923 (Folder 27: 8-11)
      - 1924 (Folder 27: 12-14)
      - 1924 (Folder 28: 1-11)
      - 1924 (Folder 29: 1-11)
      - 1924 (Folder 30: 1)
      - 1925 (Folder 30: 2-4)
      - 1926 (Folder 30: 5)
      - 1927 (Folder 30: 6-10)
      - 1927 (Folder 31: 1-10)
      - 1927 (Folder 32: 1)
      - 1928 (Folder 32: 2-6)
      - 1929 (Folder 32: 7-9)
      - 1930 (Folder 33: 1-2)
      - 1931 (Folder 33: 3-4)
      - 1932 (Folder 33: 5-9)
      - 1932 (Folder 34: 1)
      - 1933 (Folder 34: 2-5)
      - 1934 (Folder 34: 6-8)
      - 1935 (Folder 34: 9-10)
      - 1935 (Folder 35: 1-3)
      - 1936 (Folder 35: 4)
  - Lists of supporters, 1929-1935 (Folder 35: 5)
  - Mailing lists, 1926-1930 (Folder 35: 6-7)
  - Press releases and statements, 1923-1935
    - 1923-1928 (Folder 35: 8)
    - 1931-1935 (Folder 35: 9)
  - Remarks, 1924-1935 (Folder 36: 1-2)
  - Subject file, 1918-1936
    - Agricultural Adjustment Act, 1935 (Folder 36: 3-5)
    - Allied war debts, 1923-1932
      - General, 1923-1932
        - 1923-1926 (Folder 36: 6)
        - 1926 (Folder 36: 7)
        - 1926-1927 (Folder 36: 8)
        - 1926-1928 (Folder 36: 9)
        - 1932 (Folder 36: 10)
      - France, 1925-1930
        - 1925 (Folder 36: 11)
        - 1926 (Folder 36: 12, Folder 37: 1-2)
        - 1927 (Folder 37: 3)
        - 1928 (Folder 37: 4)
        - 1929 (Folder 37: 5)
        - 1930 (Folder 37: 6)
    - American soldiers buried in Russia, 1927 (Folder 37: 7)
    - Banking bill, 1935 (Folder 37: 8)
    - Boston Navy Yard, 1928-1933
      - 1928-1929 (Folder 37: 9)
      - 1930 (Folder 37: 10)
      - 1933 (Folder 37: 11)
    - Education, 1921 (Folder 37: 12)
    - Fishing industry, 1923-1933
      - 1923 (Folder 37: 13)
      - 1924 (Folder 37: 14)
      - 1925-1927 (Folder 38: 1)
      - 1932-1933 (Folder 38: 2)
    - Gloucester Harbor, 1933-1936 (Folder 38: 3)
    - Immigration, 1926-1930 (Folder 38: 4-7)
    - Inflation, 1932-1933 (Folder 38: 8-10)
    - Jusserand, Jean Jules, 1924 (Folder 39: 1)
    - Matheson Radio Company, 1930-1932 (Folder 39: 2)
    - Naval affairs, 1919-1934 (Folder 39: 3-4)
    - Navy and Marine Memorial, 1927 (Folder 39: 5)
    - Pension claims, 1918-1922
      - 1918 (Folder 39: 6-7)
      - 1919 (Folder 39: 8-11)
      - 1920 (Folder 40: 1-4)
      - 1921 (Folder 40: 5-10)
      - 1922 (Folder 41: 1-5)
    - Prohibition, 1928-1932
      - 1928 (Folder 41: 6)
      - 1929-1930 (Folder 41: 7)
      - 1930 (Folder 41: 8-9)
      - 1930 (Folder 42: 1-4)
      - 1930-1931 (Folder 42: 5-6)
      - 1931 (Folder 42: 7-8)
      - 1932 (Folder 42: 9-10)
    - Tariffs, 1923-1935
      - 1923-1929 (Folder 43: 1)
      - 1929-1934 (Folder 43: 2)
      - 1929-1935 (Folder 43: 3)
    - Trade treaties, 1934 (Folder 43: 4)
    - United States Postal Service, 1935 (Folder 43: 5)
    - Veterans, 1932-1935
      - 1932-1935 (Folder 43: 6)
      - 1935 (Folder 43: 7)
- Andrew family materials, 1832-1950 (Box 43-46)
  Contains clippings, correspondence, diary, family history, obituary, and will.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of individual and by physical form thereunder
  - Family history, 1938 (Folder 43: 8-11)
  - Andrew, Abram Piatt, Jr. (grandfather), 1832-1938
    - Clipping, 1938 (Folder 44: 1)
    - Letters to Viola Andrew, 1832-1839 (Folder 44: 2)
    - Will, 1887 (Folder 44: 3)
  - Andrew, Abram Piatt, III (father), 1852-1936
    - Clippings, 1918-1936 (Folder 44: 4)
    - Correspondence, 1863-1926 (Folder 44: 5)
    - Diary, 1852 (Folder 44: 6)
    - Obituary, 1935 (Folder 44: 7)
  - Patch, Helen Andrew (sister), 1918-1950
    - Correspondence, 1918-1950
      - Letters of condolence on the death of A. Piatt Andrew, 1936 (Folder 44: 8)
      - General, 1931-1950
        - A-K, 1931-1950 (Folder 44: 9)
        - L-Z, 1934-1945 (Folder 44: 10)
      - Bates, George J., 1936-1937 (Folder 44: 11)
      - Christie, Francis A., 1936 (Folder 44: 12)
      - Fleming, Owen, 1937-1948 (Folder 44: 13)
      - Galatti, Stephen, 1936-1946 (Folder 44: 14)
      - Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1932-1936 (Folder 44: 15)
      - Lovett, Elizabeth M., 1936 (Folder 44: 16)
      - Marlio, Rachel, 1940-1943 (Folder 44: 17)
      - Mixter, Felicie Howell, 1940 (Folder 44: 18)
      - Perouse, Maurice, 1939-1947 (Folder 44: 19)
      - Saltonstall, Leverett, 1935-1938 (Folder 44: 20)
      - Sinkler, Caroline, 1935-1937 (Folder 44: 21)
      - Sleeper, Henry Davis, 1918 (Folder 44: 22)
      - Willkie, Wendell L., 1940 (Folder 44: 23)
      - Woodbury, George W., 1940 (Folder 44: 24)
    - Subject file, 1915-1944
      - La Fayette Fund, 1915 (Folder 45: 1)
      - Massachusetts Committee on Public Safety, 1941-1943
        - Bulletins, 1941-1943 (Folder 45: 2)
        - Correspondence, 1941-1943 (Folder 45: 3)
        - Printed matter, 1942 (Folder 45: 4)
        - Questionnaires, 1942 (Folder 45: 5)
        - Reports, 1942 (Folder 45: 6)
      - Wendell Willkie presidential campaign, 1940-1944
        - Campaign literature, 1940 (Folder 45: 7)
        - Clippings, 1940-1944
          - 1940 (Folder 45: 8)
          - 1944 (Folder 45: 9)
        - Convention pass, 1940 (Folder 45: 10)
        - Correspondence, 1940 (Folder 46: 1)
        - Map showing precincts and wards of Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1940 (Folder 46: 2)
        - Press releases, 1940 (Folder 46: 3)
- Subject file, 1901-1932 (Box 46-47)
  Contains brochures, clippings, correspondence, and reports
  Arranged by subject
  - Boer War, 1901-1902 (Folder 46: 4)
  - Currency, 1901-1906 (Folder 46: 5)
  - Disarmament, 1930 (Folder 46: 6)
  - Economics, 1901-1930 (Folder 46: 7)
  - Fishing industry, 1912-1914 (Folder 46: 8)
  - France - Economic conditions, 1923-1925 (Folder 46: 9)
  - Guynemer, Georges, 1918 (Folder 46: 10)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1928 (Folder 46: 11)
  - Lefévere, Kamiel, 1928-1931 (Folder 46: 12)
  - Libby, Frederick J., 1927-1928 (Folder 47: 1)
  - United States - Politics and government, 1923-1925 (Folder 47: 2)
  - World War I, 1927-1932 (Folder 47: 3)
- Photographs, 1848-1938 (Box 47-48)
  Contains prints
  Arranged by subject and chronologically thereunder
  - A. Piatt Andrew, 1887-1937
    - Andrew, A. Piatt with a group of fellow schoolboys, 1887 (Folder 47: 4)
    - Andrew, A. Piatt with traveling companions in Switzerland, 1891 (Folder 47: 5)
    - Andrew, A. Piatt, 1898 (Folder 47: 6)
    - Andrew, A. Piatt, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1905 (Folder 47: 7)
    - Andrew, A. Piatt and friends, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1905 (Folder 47: 8)
    - Andrew, A. Piatt, Red Roof, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1910 (Folder 47: 9)
    - Scenes of A. Piatt Andrew?s residence and vicinity, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1910 (Folder 47: 10)
    - Andrew, A. Piatt, 1911 (Folder 47: 11)
    - Andrew, A. Piatt and Léon Théodor, 1915 (Folder 47: 12)
    - Andrew, A. Piatt with members of the American Field Service and French officers, France, 1916-1917 (Folder 47: 13)
    - Andrew, A. Piatt, 1920 (Folder 47: 14)
    - Andrew, A. Piatt, 1935 (Folder 47: 15)
    - Andrew, A. Piatt, 1936 (Folder 47: 16)
    - Memorial ceremony honoring A. Piatt Andrew, 1936 (Folder 47: 17)
    - Bust of A. Piatt Andrew, Blérancourt, France, 1938 (Folder 47: 18)
  - Andrew family, 1848-1920
    - Andrew, Viola Armstrong, 1848 (Folder 48: 1)
    - Andrew family residence, Indiana, 1880 (Folder 48: 2)
    - Andrew, Abram Piatt, Jr., 1886 (Folder 48: 3)
    - Andrew, Hoosierette, 1890 (Folder 48: 4)
    - Andrew, Catharine Piatt, 1920 (Folder 48: 5)
  - Others, 1850-1907
    - Marrell, G. W., 1850 (Folder 48: 6)
    - Corm, Sophie, 1894 (Folder 48: 7)
    - Hogarty, Viola Collins, 1907 (Folder 48: 8)
  - Unidentified, 1890-1920
    - Military officer, Bogotá, Colombia, 1890 (Folder 48: 9)
    - Young man, Boston, Massachusetts, 1890 (Folder 48: 10)
    - Young woman, Indianapolis, Indiana, 1890 (Folder 48: 10)
    - Picnic group, 1890 (Folder 48: 11)
    - Two children, Switzerland, 1897 (Folder 48: 12)
    - Young woman, Louisville, Kentucky, 1897 (Folder 48: 13)
    - Child, 1900 (Folder 48: 14)
    - Two men, 1900 (Folder 48: 15)
    - Three young women, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1910 (Folder 48: 16)
    - Two men walking on beach, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1910 (Folder 48: 17)
    - Young man, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1910 (Folder 48: 18)
    - Young woman, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1910 (Folder 48: 19)
    - Young woman at window, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1910 (Folder 48: 20)
    - Young woman walking on beach, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1910 (Folder 48: 21)
    - Woman standing by wall, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1910 (Folder 48: 22)
    - American Field Service member, France, 1915 (Folder 48: 23)
    - American Field Service personnel and French soldiers, France, 1916 (Folder 48: 24)
    - Group of sailors and others at luncheon, 1920 (Folder 48: 25)
- Printed matter, 1902-1919 (Box 49)
  Contains pamphlets, monograph and serial issue, largely relating to banking and currency issues
  - Monograph and serial issue, 1911-1919
    - Vanderlip, Frank A., Modern Banking, 1911 (Folder 49: 1)
    - Cartoons Magazine, 1919 March (Folder 49: 2)
  - Pamphlets relating to banking and currency issues, 1902-1913 (Folder 49: 3-22)
- Oversize materials, 1909-1936 (Box 50-60)
  Contains scrapbooks of clippings relating to the life of A. Piatt Andrew
  - Charts produced by the National Monetary Commission, 1909 (Folder 50: 1-23)
  - Photographs, 1910-1922
    - Interior view of A. Piatt Andrew?s residence, Red Roof, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1910 (Folder 50: 24)
    - Exterior view of A. Piatt Andrew?s residence, Red Roof, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1910 (Folder 50: 25)
    - Andrew, A. Piatt and others at costume party, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1911 (Folder 50: 26)
    - Interior view, Fenway Court, Boston, Massachusetts, 1912 (Folder 50: 27)
    - Andrew, A. Piatt, Gloucester, Massachusetts, 1922 (Folder 50: 28)
  - Posters, 1919-1942
    - Notice of time change issued by French interior ministry, 1919 (Folder 50: 29)